Howard McClusky Collection
Howard McClusky Collection
- Tapes
  - AT48: Dr. McClusky – WOM (Box 12)
  - AT49: Dr. McClusky – W5M (Box 12)
  - AT50: McClusky symposium, AAACE, November, part 1, 2002 (Box 12)
  - AT51: McClusky symposium, AAACE, November, part 2, 2002 (Box 12)
- Miscellaneous
  - MS-1: Early AEA newsletters from McClusky’s first year as association president (Box 13)
  - MS-18: A Brochure of Community Adult Education of The University of Michigan, McClusky was a member of staff (Box 13)
  - MS-21: Statistical Data Based on attendance at Area Conference from 1947-1954 (Box 13)
  - MS-22: McClusky's list of Michigan places having or having had community councils, 1938-1955 (Box 13)
  - MS-64: Bibliographical List of McClusky’s works, undated (Box 13)
  - MS-67: "Howard Yale McClusky: Adult education pioneer statesman, " later published in Lifelong Learning, February 1, 1980 (Box 13)
  - MS-79: Group Interaction Charts, 1943-1944 (Box 13)
  - MS-86: Selected Biographical Items (Professional), 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - MS-89: Bibliographical Collections of McClusky and others, undated (Box 13)
  - MS-90: McClusky Interview, p. 190 of an abstract by Christine Thompson Wilson, undated (Box 13)
  - MS-92: Miscellaneous adult education material relating to McClusky (Box 13)
  - MS-93: McClusky on "emotional maturity," quoted at length by Raleigh Schooling in Student Teaching, 1949 (Box 13)
  - MS-98: American Youth and the Present Crisis, May 1941; proceedings of the Seventh Conference on Education and the Exceptional Child (Box 13)
  - MS-104: The Department of Post-Graduate Medicine: A History and Interpretation of its development, by Joan Mason Karr, undated; McClusky was a member of her doctoral committee (Box 13)
  - MS-105: A Collection of the Michigan Newsletter, 1946; 1947-1953,; 1964; copies (Box 13)
  - MS-109: Report of the Committee on Education, undated; McClusky was Chairman of the committee (Box 13)
  - MS-113.2: "Howard Yale McClusky," by Roger Hiemstra, November, 1985; paper presented at the National Adult Education Conference (Box 13)
  - MS-116.1: The psychology and education of older persons, a conference in Guelph (Canada), May 13-14, 1982 (Box 13)
  - MS-117: Letters of condolence to Helen McClusky regarding McClusky’s death (Box 13)
  - MS-118: American Youth Commission materials when Howard worked with them, 1937-1939 (Box 13)
  - MS-122.1: List of Howard’s speeches, activities, and honors, 1926-1979 (Box 13)
  - MS-123.1: McClusky bibliography (Box 13)
  - MS-124.1: Tribute to McClusky, February, 1980 (Box 13)
  - MS-139.1: Material related to programming for older adults, Canada, 1979 (Box 13)
  - MS-139.2: Sample of a typical final exam for a Howard McClusky course (Box 13)
  - MS-140: Description of Howard McClusky material at the University of Michigan Historical Library (Box 13)
  - MS-157: A summary of discussion and ideas introduced at a seminar from co-author, Roger Hiemstra, January 12, 1970 (Box 13)
  - MS-213: Dr. McClusky as a member of a Panel on Aging and the Adult Learner: Theories and Models, under the Commission of the Professors of Adult Education, November 3, 1980 (Box 13)
  - MS-225: Program of the First Annual Institute on Small Community Life, May 27-29, 1946; McClusky is listed as having two presentations (Box 13)
  - MS-335: A history of community adult education at the University of Michigan, 1938-1953, the first fifteen years, Cynthia M. Jones, September, 1955 (Box 13)
  - MS-339: Qualifying examination for the doctoral candidacy of Michael Day, August 1, 1979; topic was McClusky (Box 13)
  - MS-343: University of Michigan School of Education publications with tributes to McClusky (Box 13)
  - MS-344: Information on McClusky’s parents from Blackburn College (Box 13)
  - MS-345: Information from a Park College yearbook, McClusky obtained his undergraduate degree at Park College (Box 13)
  - MS-346: McClusky photos (Box 13)